<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Components on Drafting Strategy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58290/components/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Components on Drafting Strategy</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Larson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 04:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58290/components/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58290/exploring-for-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58290/exploring-for-strategy/</guid>
      <description>A surprising number of strategies are doomed from inception because their authors get attached to one particular approach without considering alternatives that would work better for their current circumstances. This happens when engineers want to pick tools solely because they are trending, and when executives insist on adopting the tech stack from their prior organization where they felt comfortable.&#xA;Exploration is the antidote to early anchoring, forcing you to consider the problem widely before evaluating any of the paths forward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58290/diagnosis-for-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58290/diagnosis-for-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve written your strategy&amp;rsquo;s exploration, the next step is working on its diagnosis. Diagnosis is understanding the constraints and challenges your strategy needs to address. In particular, it&amp;rsquo;s about doing that understanding while slowing yourself down from deciding how to solve the problem at hand before you know the problem&amp;rsquo;s nuances and constraints.&#xA;If you ever find yourself wanting to skip the diagnosis phase&amp;ndash;let&amp;rsquo;s get to the solution already!&amp;ndash;then maybe it&amp;rsquo;s worth acknowledging that every strategy that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen fail, did so due to a lazy or inaccurate diagnosis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refining</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58290/refining-eng-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58290/refining-eng-strategy/</guid>
      <description>In Jim Collins&amp;rsquo; Great by Choice, he develops the concept of Fire Bullets, Then Cannonballs. His premise is that you should cheaply test new ideas before fully committing to them. Your organization can only afford firing a small number of cannonballs, but it can bankroll far more bullets. Why not use bullets to derisk your cannonballs&amp;rsquo; trajectories?&#xA;This chapter presents a series of concrete techniques that I have personally used to effectively refine strategies before reaching the cannonball stage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58290/policy-for-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58290/policy-for-strategy/</guid>
      <description>This book&amp;rsquo;s introduction started by defining strategy as &amp;ldquo;making decisions.&amp;rdquo; Then we dug into exploration, diagnosis, and refinement: three chapters where you could argue that we didn&amp;rsquo;t decide anything at all. Clarifying the problem to be solved is the prerequisite of effective decision making, but eventually decisions do have to be made. Here in this chapter on policy, and the following chapter on operations, we finally start to actually make some decisions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58290/operations-for-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58290/operations-for-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Even the best policies fail if they aren&amp;rsquo;t adopted by the teams they&amp;rsquo;re intended to serve. Can we persistently change our company&amp;rsquo;s behaviors with a one-time announcement? No, probably not.&#xA;I refer to the art of making policies work as &amp;ldquo;operations&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;strategy operations.&amp;rdquo; The good news is that effectively operating a policy is two-thirds avoiding common practices that simply don&amp;rsquo;t work. The other one-third takes some practice, but can be practiced in any engineering role: there&amp;rsquo;s no need to wait until you&amp;rsquo;re an executive to start building mastery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making engineering strategies more readable</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58290/readable-engineering-strategy-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58290/readable-engineering-strategy-documents/</guid>
      <description>As discussed in Components of engineering strategy, a complete engineering strategy has five components: explore, diagnose, refine (map &amp;amp; model), policy, and operation. However, it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite challenging to read a strategy document written that way. That&amp;rsquo;s an effective sequence for creating a strategy, but it&amp;rsquo;s a challenging sequence for those trying to quickly read and apply a strategy without necessarily wanting to understand the complete thinking behind each decision.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging theory and practice in engineering strategy.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58290/bridging-eng-strategy-theory-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58290/bridging-eng-strategy-theory-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>Some people I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with have lost hope that engineering strategy actually exists within any engineering organizations. I imagine that they, reading through the steps to build engineering strategy, or the strategy for navigating private equity ownership, are not impressed. Instead, these ideas probably come across as theoretical at best. In less polite company, they might describe these ideas as fake constructs.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it! Because they&amp;rsquo;re right. In fact, they&amp;rsquo;re right in two different ways.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
