<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Systems-Thinking on </title>
    <link>//localhost:50916/tags/systems-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Systems-Thinking on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 05:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:50916/tags/systems-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Service onboarding model for Uber (2014).</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/uber-strategy-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/uber-strategy-model/</guid>
      <description>At the core of Uber&amp;rsquo;s service migration strategy (2014) is understanding the service onboarding process, and identifying the levers to speed up that process. Here we&amp;rsquo;ll develop a system model representing that onboarding process, and exercise the model to test a number of hypotheses about how to best speed up provisioning.&#xA;In this chapter, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover:&#xA;Where the model of service onboarding suggested we focus on efforts Developing a system model using the lethain/systems package on Github.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling impact of LLMs on Developer Experience.</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/llm-adoption-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/llm-adoption-model/</guid>
      <description>In How should you adopt Large Language Models? (LLMs), we considered how LLMs might impact a company&amp;rsquo;s developer experience. To support that exploration, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a system model of the software development process at the company.&#xA;In this chapter, we&amp;rsquo;ll work through:&#xA;Summary results from this model How the model was developed, both sketching and building the model in a spreadsheet. (As discussed in the overview of systems modeling, I generally would recommend against using spreadsheets to develop most models, but it&amp;rsquo;s educational to attempt doing so once or twice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling driving onboarding.</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/llm-onboarding-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/llm-onboarding-model/</guid>
      <description>The How should you adopt LLMs? strategy explores how Theoretical Ride Sharing might adopt LLMs. It builds on several models, the first is about LLMs impact on Developer Experience. The second model, documented here, looks at whether LLMs might improve a core product and business problem: maximizing active drivers on their ridesharing platform.&#xA;In this chapter, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover:&#xA;Where the model of ridesharing drivers identifies opportunities for LLMs How the model was sketched and developed using lethain/systems package on Github Exercising this model to learn from it Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eng org seniority-mix model.</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/private-equity-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/private-equity-model/</guid>
      <description>One of the trademarks of private equity ownership is the expectation that either the company maintains their current margin and grows revenue at 25-30%, or they instead grow slower and increase their free cash flow year over year. In many organizations, engineering costs have a major impact on their free cash flow. There are many costs to reduce, cloud hosting and such, but inevitably part of the discussion is addressing engineering headcount costs directly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systems model of API deprecation</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/api-deprecation-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/api-deprecation-model/</guid>
      <description>In How should Stripe deprecate APIs?, the diagnosis depends on the claim that deprecating APIs is a significant cause of customer churn. While there is internal data that can be used to correlate deprecation with churn, it&amp;rsquo;s also valuable to build a model to help us decide if we believe that correlation and causation are aligned in this case.&#xA;In this chapter, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover:&#xA;What we learn from modeling API deprecation&amp;rsquo;s impact on user retention Developing a system model using the lethain/systems package on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
