<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wardley on </title>
    <link>//localhost:50916/tags/wardley/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wardley on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 04:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:50916/tags/wardley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refining strategy with Wardley Mapping.</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/wardley-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/wardley-mapping/</guid>
      <description>The first time I heard about Wardley Mapping was from Charity Majors discussing it on Twitter. Of the three core strategy refinement techniques, this is the technique that I&amp;rsquo;ve personally used the least. Despite that, I decided to include it in this book because it highlights how many different techniques can be used for refining strategy, and also because it&amp;rsquo;s particularly effective at looking at the broader ecosystems your organization exists in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wardley mapping the service orchestration ecosystem (2014).</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/uber-strategy-wardley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/uber-strategy-wardley/</guid>
      <description>In Uber&amp;rsquo;s 2014 service migration strategy, we explore how to navigate the move from a Python monolith to a services-oriented architecture while also scaling with user traffic that doubled every six months.&#xA;This Wardley map explores how orchestration frameworks were evolving during that period to be used as an input into determining the most effective path forward for Uber&amp;rsquo;s Infrastructure Engineering team.&#xA;Reading this map To quickly understand this Wardley Map, read from top to bottom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wardley mapping the LLM ecosystem.</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/wardley-llm-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/wardley-llm-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>In How should you adopt LLMs?, we explore how a theoretical ride sharing company, Theoretical Ride Sharing, should adopt Large Language Models (LLMs). Part of that strategy&amp;rsquo;s diagnosis depends on understanding the expected evolution of the LLM ecosystem, which we&amp;rsquo;ve built a Wardley map to better explore.&#xA;This map of the LLM space focuses on how product companies should address the proliferation of model providers such as Anthropic, Google and OpenAI, as well as the proliferation of LLM product patterns like agentic workflows, Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), and running evals to maintain performance as models change.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
