<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Refinement on </title>
    <link>//localhost:50916/refinement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Refinement on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:50916/refinement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to refinement tools</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/refinement-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/refinement-intro/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps the most important piece of the Steps to build an engineering strategy is strategy refinement. As we already worked through the overview of strategy refinement in the &amp;ldquo;Steps&amp;rdquo; section of this book, the goal of the &amp;ldquo;Refinement&amp;rdquo; section is to go into much greater detail about the three core mapping techniques: strategy testing, systems modeling, and Wardley mapping.&#xA;As we work through them, keep in mind that there are many other techniques out there, such as the many covered in Eben Hewitt&amp;rsquo;s Technology Strategy Patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategy testing: avoid the waterfall strategy trap with iterative refinement.</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/strategy-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/strategy-testing/</guid>
      <description>If I could only popularize one idea about technical strategy, it would be that prematurely applying pressure to a strategy&amp;rsquo;s rollout prevents evaluating whether the strategy is effective. Pressure changes behavior in profound ways, and many of those changes are intended to make you believe your strategy is working while minimizing change to the status quo (if you&amp;rsquo;re an executive) or get your strategy repealed (if you&amp;rsquo;re not an executive). Neither is particular helpful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using systems modeling to refine strategy.</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/systems-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/systems-modeling/</guid>
      <description>While I was probably late to learn the concept of strategy testing, I might have learned about systems modeling too early in my career, stumbling on Donella Meadows&amp;rsquo; Thinking in Systems: A Primer before I began my career in software. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered a number of ways to misuse systems modeling, but it remains the most effective, flexible tool I&amp;rsquo;ve found to debugging complex problems.&#xA;In this chapter, we&amp;rsquo;ll work through:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refining strategy with Wardley Mapping.</title>
      <link>//localhost:50916/wardley-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:50916/wardley-mapping/</guid>
      <description>The first time I heard about Wardley Mapping was from Charity Majors discussing it on Twitter. Of the three core strategy refinement techniques, this is the technique that I&amp;rsquo;ve personally used the least. Despite that, I decided to include it in this book because it highlights how many different techniques can be used for refining strategy, and also because it&amp;rsquo;s particularly effective at looking at the broader ecosystems your organization exists in.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
